# **Barnice Wakiro**

+254(0)740457499 | wakirowambui@gmail.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I am enthusiastic about Cybersecurity and enjoy finding solutions that can positively impact an organization and the people it serves. I place a high value on communication and building relationships with stakeholders, learning quickly on the job, research and asking the right questions to help contribute to the success of the organization's mission.

#### **EDUCATION**

**USIU- Cyber Shujaa** Nairobi, Kenya

Graduation Date: Jun 2024 Cloud and network Security

**Africa International University** Nairobi, Kenya

Bachelor of science in information Technology Graduation Date: Oct 2021

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**Kenya Revenue Authority** Nairobi, Kenya Security Analyst Intern Nov 2023 - Present

• Writting weekly and monthly reports for the soc team.

- Performing Network reconnaissance as directed by the team lead.
- Collaborating on simulation attacks for bussiness continuity planning/
- Monitoring and analyzing offenses on IIBM Qradar SIEM.
- Blocking malicious ip addresses on the firewall.
- collaborating with other security teams.
- Conduting research on the latest cybersecurity treands.

**Angel Technologies** Nairobi, Kenya Mar 2023 - Sep 2023

Laptop sales rep

- Engage with customers in a professional and friendly manner to understand their laptop needs and preferences.
- Demonstrate and explain the features and benefits of various laptop models to customers.
- Assist customers with product demonstrations, including setting up and configuring laptops.
- Process sales transactions accurately and efficiently using our POS (Point of Sale) system.

Kenya Revenue Authority Nairobi, Kenya Jan 2022 - Dec 2022 IT Support Intern

Support the IT team in Maintaining Hardware, Software, and other Systems.

- Assist in Asset Management and resolving incident and service request tickets.
- Providing technical support and troubleshooting network problems.
- Installation and Configuration of computer hardware, OS, and software applications.
- Configured and maintained network printers, scanners, and other peripherals.
- Provided technical support to staff members in troubleshooting and resolving computer and software-related issues.
- Provided guidance to staff members on how to operate new software and computerequipment.

## AFRICA INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

Nairobi, Kenya

Feb 2021 - May 2021

IT Support Attachee

Assisted in troubleshooting hardware and software issues, providing technical support to end-users.

- Conducted software and hardware instalations for staff and the computer labs.
- Assisted in network administration tasks, such as configuring routers and switches.
- Supported IT projects by performing research, documentation, and assisting in project implementation.
- Collaborated with team members to streamline IT processes and improve efficiency.

#### **SKILLS**

Ms Office Suite, SQL, TCP/IP, cybersecurity tools, Windows/ linux OS, Python, MYSQL/PostgreSQL, computer networks github, Documentation, Research, Team viewer, git&github, Team Collaboration, Troubleshooting and Technical Support ,communication skills,Problem Solving,Adaptability.

## **CERTIFICATION**

Google IT Support Professional Certificate Google, ISC2 | Certified in Cybersecurity